Dale Conboy

Senior Front End Developer at Apple

Summary

Front end web developer with PHP and MySQL back end experience, complimented by nearly 15 years of graphic design and a lifetime of illustration. Additional experience includes online marketing and marketing automation system (MAS) implementation, setup and operation.

Specialties: Web Development, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, PHP, Website Design, Graphic Design, Web Collateral Design, Online Marketing and Marketing Automation Systems.

Experience

Senior Front End Developer at Apple

May 2014 - Present

Front end web development for apple.com. Using HTML5, CSS3, and vanilla javascript to build web pages. Also contributing to internal javascript libraries.

Front End Developer at Apple

September 2012 - May 2014 (1 year 8 months)

Front end web development for apple.com. Using HTML5, CSS3, and vanilla javascript to build web pages. Also contributing to internal javascript libraries.

Freelance Web Development and Graphic Design

January 1998 - December 2013 (15 years 11 months)

Ongoing contract and freelance design work since 1998 for both print and web in addition to web development and website creation projects. Clients range from small businesses and independent entrepreneurs to medium size corporations.

Front End Developer at SolutionSet

August 2011 - September 2012 (1 year 1 month)

Front end web development for various client projects utilizing bleeding edge web technologies such as HTML5, CSS3, and javascript.

Projects Included:

Google - On-site development as a front end dev team lead at the client's offices in Mountain View.

Apple Inc. - On-site work at Apple's offices in Cupertino.

Lead Web Developer at GoGrid

September 2010 - August 2011 (11 months)

Promoted to Lead Web Developer. Managed the web development team and was responsible for development and upkeep of all publicly facing web properties.

Web Developer at GoGrid

June 2008 - September 2010 (2 years 3 months)

Converted from a contractor to full time employee.

Contract Web Developer at GoGrid

February 2008 - June 2008 (4 months)

Full time on-site contractor for GoGrid's Marketing and Web Development teams.

Production Manager

September 2004 - December 2007 (3 years 3 months)

Built and scaled the production department from the business' inception, including implementing efficient job tracking and production workflows. Hired and managed a production crew of four with whom I shared production art and design responsibilities.

Graphic Designer, Production Artist

August 2000 - December 2003 (3 years 4 months)

Graphic Designer, Sign Maker

September 1996 - June 2000 (3 years 9 months)

Education

Humboldt State University

Studio Art, Graphic Design, Painting, Photography, 1998 - 2000

College of the Redwoods

General education, Art, 1996 - 1998

Honors and Awards

Published Illustrationsmusic, soccer, drums, snowboarding, art, web design, graphic design, web development, technology

Dale Conboy

Senior Front End Developer at Apple



Contact Dale on LinkedIn